Who am I here with today?
Daymond John.
Kendra Scott.
Are you a business owner?
I am. I'm one of only
20 female founders in the United States
that have founded a billion dollar brand.
So you founded a billion dollar company?
A billion dollar company with a B.
Yes.
Yeah.
What was the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
In 2019, I sold 76 companies for $1.27 billion.
The most amount of money the
company ever made was $980 million.
In profit.
In profit?
Yeah.
That's incredible.
It is pretty good.
How can somebody become a
multimillionaire in 2024 like yourself?
Hard Knocks family.
I'm out in Houston, Texas
right now at the Aspire Tour,
which is one of the largest
business conferences in the entire world.
We're VIP today, so we're
going to be interviewing eight, nine
and even billion dollar entrepreneurs to
figure out how they created their wealth
and their best advice to any entrepreneurs
trying to build multimillion
dollar businesses in today's world.
So with that being said, let's go interview these moguls
and let's go see what they have to say.
Who am I here with today?
Kendra Scott.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
So jewelry and accessories.
Yeah.
Retail, wholesale, I'm omnichannel, baby.
Ecom, all of it.
Are you a business owner?
I am.
I'm one of only 20 female founders in the
United States that have founded a billion dollar brand.
So you founded a billion dollar company?
A billion dollar company.
With a B.
Yes.
Yeah.
What's the secret to building a billion dollar brand?
So my first collection I did with $500.
And then I was able to write some orders.
I had a decent amount of margin.
I was able to reinvest in the business.
Nobody would invest in me for 10 years.
I went to multiple investors.
Nobody would give me a dime.
Even though I was selling to
big department stores and other people,
no one believed in retail.
So I had to do it on
a line of credit, credit card debt.
I put everything I owned up for collateral.
I bootstrapped this baby all the way.
But as we started to get
success, one of my mentors said,
if you build it, you're going
to make a lot of money.
So I started to build it.
They will come.
Boy, was he right.
When I started having lines around
the block and people coming in,
they were like all these
PE firms and venture capital firms
were ringing my phone.
And they're like, how do we
get engaged and involved in this business?
Keep your head down.
Build a profitable business.
Not just a business that looks good top line.
You've got to have EBITDA, baby.
You've got to be making money.
And that is what everybody is looking for today.
10 years in, we were able to bring investors.
And here we are continuing to grow.
What was the best advice that
you ever got from a mentor?
Look, we always talk about people feeling
like you've got to fake it
till you make it, whatever it is.
I totally disagree with that.
But you can't be intimidated.
Success is a mindset.
My father always said, honey, don't be intimidated
by the men in suits.
I've walked into so many
rooms and nobody in that room
looked like me.
And I had to have that confidence within myself
to know I know what I'm talking about.
I know that I can do this.
And I'm not going to let anybody scare me today.
Have that confidence.
Have that ability.
Because there's always going to be somebody
that will want to intimidate you.
You've got to walk in
there and be like, watch out.
Here I come.
So as a billion dollar business owner,
you've been at the table with some heavy hitters.
And you've had to negotiate and close
some massive deals, I'm sure.
What is your best negotiation advice
for people that are in those rooms
with those kind of people that may struggle with closing
deals in today's world?
Look, I always say I'm a sponge.
I want to hear what these folks have to say.
And I try to really understand their perspective.
But at the same time, I'm
going to come back with that.
And I've already done my research.
I've done my homework.
And I came in prepared.
Don't go to any negotiation or any contract negotiation
without doing your homework.
Know exactly who is going
to be sitting in that room.
Know their backgrounds.
Know other deals that they've done.
Talk to other people that have done deals with them.
And you're going to bring
out things out of your hat.
And they're going to go, whoa.
How does she know that?
How did she hear about that?
I always am surprising them.
And that is the art of negotiating,
is you've got to be able to surprise your opponent
with a little bit of a punch right
when they least suspect it.
You've got amazing advice.
Thank you so much for your time.
I really appreciate that.
Thank you so much.
For our Knox family, we just interviewed business legend
Kendra Scott, who's one of only 20 female entrepreneurs who
built a billion dollar company from scratch.
Like she said, she started this company with only $500
and turned it into a multi, multi-billion dollar empire.
That was an insane interview, you guys.
What did she say?
You have to walk into any room, any sales meeting,
any negotiation with the confidence
it doesn't matter who's on the other side of there,
that you prepare to win and that you can make
incredible things happen.
Great interview with Kendra Scott, you guys.
Let's go see who else we can find, man.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Question for you.
Have you ever been broke before?
I've been broke and I've never been broke.
Yeah?
And what do you do for
living out here in Houston, Texas?
I'm in private equity.
You're in private equity?
Yeah.
Now, I go all over the country just asking
people how they made it for the younger generation.
Could I get just one
minute of your time real quick?
Sure.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
In 2019, I sold 76 companies for $1.27 billion.
$1.27 billion.
Yeah.
And do you come from a lot of money?
No.
No?
What was the number one book that changed your life?
Yeah, my number one book is
Ego is the Enemy by Ryan Holiday.
So good.
Number one takeaway from that book?
That everything that you want is on the other side
of your ego.
You've got to get your ego out of the way.
Use people to get to where you need to go.
Do you think everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
No, absolutely not.
Why not?
Because there's a lot of people out there
who have a hustle and a grind that's absolutely necessary
that most people are not
willing to put the effort into.
At what point as an
entrepreneur is it time to diversify?
When you have a system and process that's replicatable.
If you focus on the actual system,
then it doesn't matter what you do.
I run 86 companies at the same time, right?
So everybody that tells you to focus on one thing,
they just don't know how
to have a process and system
to do multiple.
You could run 10 businesses yourself if you wanted to.
So you're running 86 companies.
How is that possible?
It's possible because I have a system and process that
gives me all data.
I'm data analyst at the top.
I have people that I empower.
And then they run the same system
across every single company, no matter what it is.
So it's all about people and systems, it seems like.
All about people and systems.
You're in private equity.
You're in the money business.
What's the best industry people should be
looking to get into in 2024?
Right now, AI and tech.
I mean, AI and tech's everything.
Why is that?
Because it has the greatest opportunity for scale.
Everyone knows they need it.
They don't quite have it yet.
And it's going to take over so much
of our computational processing in our businesses.
So we're on our way to
go get our next interview right now.
But I want to take a
moment to talk to you guys
about some of the greatest
advice I've ever received while running this channel.
One of the best decisions you
will ever make with your money
is learning how to make that money work for you.
But I'll go a step further.
Just as it's important to invest back into yourself
and your business, you need
to invest in your family's future.
And that's why I want to take a moment
to talk about the sponsor of today's video.
Fabric by Gerber Life.
Fabric was made for parents to
make it easy to plan for
and manage your family's financial path.
With the kids investment account from Fabric,
you can start investing in
your child's future starting today.
While your kids can invest when they're minors,
you can set up an investment account through Fabric
and invest on their behalf.
So you can start making that money work for them
even when they're young.
And by the time they're older and ready to make
financial decisions for themselves,
they'll have a nice nest egg they're ready to go.
The funds in Fabric can be used for nearly anything
to benefit your child from paying for college tuition,
going to summer camp, even starting a side hustle.
And by the time they become adults,
they can use that money
to buy a first time home,
a car, or even starting that next business.
And one more thing, guys.
One of the greatest lessons I've learned being in business
over the last few years is you have
to be very careful with the people that you trust.
From grants.
To people.
To employees.
To partnerships.
To absolutely everything.
And Fabric has partnered up with Gerber Life,
who's been trusted by millions of families just like yours
for over 50 years.
So join the thousands of parents who trust Fabric
to help protect their families.
And start investing in your child today
at meetfabric.com slash hard knocks.
That's meetfabric.com slash hard knocks.
How are you doing, sir?
How are you?
What is your name?
James Dumar.
Who am I here with today?
Me?
Who am I?
I'm Marcus Limones.
You may know me from The Profit.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I wanted to go in an industry that
had a lot of white space, where there was not
a lot of competitors.
So I got into the RV business, which
was shocking to my family because they were like,
you're not an RVer.
But I got into it
because I knew that the consolidation
opportunity was really clear.
And the ability to get into places that were unregulated
made it really easy.
So 20 years ago, it was zero.
And today, it's a $7 billion business.
What was the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
The most amount of money the company ever made
was $980 million.
$980 million.
In profit.
Yeah.
That's incredible.
It is pretty good.
But that doesn't always happen.
And I think the key to that is understanding
that you're going to have good times and bad times.
You've got to find the
middle and be comfortable with it.
How important was it for you to master delegation?
A lot of entrepreneurs, they want
to be that solopreneur and wear all the hats themselves.
How important was it for you building teams
and bringing the right people in?
Delegation's important.
But what was more important to me
was surrounding myself with people
that were smarter than me and that had the willingness
to say no to me and
had the willingness to tell me
when I was wrong and challenge me.
And I think as people build teams,
I oftentimes see a lot of business owners
that want to build, hire people that are maybe not
as smart as them.
Instead, hire people that are wicked smart, that
make you look stupid, because you're
going to end up being
the smartest person in the room
for hiring them.
One in four millionaires are living paycheck to paycheck.
From your perspective, what keeps people
broke in today's world?
Wanting to be flashier than they should.
Thinking that perception of what they look like
is more important than who they are.
And I think oftentimes, what kind of car I drive
and the house that I live in.
What's Warren Buffett drive?
Do you know?
Not a supercar.
A Honda or?
He drives an old beater.
He lives in the same house.
You want to know why?
Because he realizes that's not where the substance is.
That doesn't mean that you can't have nice things,
but there's a balance between being substantive and flashy.
And I think too often, people
are too willing to do this.
But I will tell you that
every single person is one decision
away from losing it all.
But if you don't go up here
and you stay here, if you lose it,
it's not a big deal.
You're like, oh, I don't care.
I'll just live in a studio apartment again.
Sometimes people put material things around them
because they think it makes them look better or stronger
or more powerful.
I don't believe it.
And your last message to the younger generation?
Have the confidence that you are
just as smart as everybody else.
And don't let age be a barrier to you
getting a seat at the table.
Too oftentimes, big executives think that if you're young,
you don't know what you're doing.
You don't have enough experience.
Prove to them by having the right information,
doing the right research, outworking them
every single day, and never be entitled to anything.
Tell people that you're willing to work for it.
And if other people in the room are not
willing to work, you push them
aside, and you show up first,
and you leave last.
You got amazing advice.
Thank you, brother.
Guys, $980 million in profit.
We just interviewed Marcus Limones,
who's the founder of a company
that did over a billion dollars
in revenue in a single year.
Crazy out here.
What did he say was the secret
to going to a billion dollar company?
It wasn't just delegating, but finding people
that were smarter than him
to make the right decisions that
ultimately led to him being
able to scale that company out
to what it turned into.
Great interview out here in Houston, man.
Come on, let's go get this next one.
This video's been insane, you guys.
Let's go.
Who am I here with today?
Damon John.
And what industry did you
decide to pursue a career in?
Fashion.
How long have you been a business owner for?
40 years.
What was the best financial advice
that you ever received throughout your career?
Money's a great slave, but a horrible master.
You had a quote, pioneers get slaughtered,
and settlers prosper.
You say it again?
I forgot that one.
Pioneers get slaughtered, and settlers prosper.
That's exactly what happened.
Could you say that and break that down?
You said it.
Pioneers get slaughtered, and settlers prosper.
Break that down for people that may not understand.
Well, a lot of pioneers, if
you could be too early on something,
and nobody gets it, and you keep talking,
oh, I want to be a pioneer.
I want to do what I want to do.
But nobody gets it.
Move on.
But the ones who are
like, I want to do it.
Let me take my time.
Let me settle.
Let me figure it out.
How can somebody become a multimillionaire in 2024
like yourself?
Well, what is a multimillionaire?
Somebody that creates financial freedom.
Somebody that's aspiring to kind of achieve that success.
Well, if they're sick as shit.
Then it doesn't matter.
Then it's not a multimillionaire.
Hard Knocks family, this video has been insane so far.
But I want you to comment down below
who's been your favorite interview so far and why.
I love connecting with you guys, and I
want to know what you guys think about this video.
With that being said, let's go get this next interview.
Who am I here with today?
I'm Billy Ray Taylor, CEO of LinkedXL and author
of the book, The Winning Link.
How old are you now?
I'm 57.
And if you were to go back in time
and have a conversation with your 20-year-old self,
when you were starting from zero,
what's the best advice you
would give to your younger self?
If a bird lands on the
branch, does the bird trust the branch
or does it trust its wings?
And the clue, I've seen many birds land on branches.
But what I've never seen is a branch break
and a bird fall and die.
Trust your wings.
Wow.
How long have you been a business owner for?
Five years.
I branched off and started my own company called LinkedXL.
What was the most amount of money
that you've ever made in a single year?
Well over seven figures.
Seven figures.
Yeah.
Give me a range.
Between one and three.
One and $3 million.
That's me personal.
What's the greatest lesson that you've
learned about entrepreneurship that you'd
pass on to someone about to start
their first business in 2024?
Deliberate clarity.
You can't manage a secret.
Who was the most important person that you
met throughout your career?
My mom.
Was she a business owner or?
Well, of a house.
But she taught me the most valuable lesson.
And she said, start with a stand.
What you accept, you can't change.
So if you don't set the standard, the best coaches,
the best leaders, right?
Think a home plate in baseball.
It's 17 inches.
If you play little league baseball, high school baseball,
it's the standard.
Coaches don't widen the plate.
You got to play to the standard.
And then what you accept, you can't change.
What you accept.
In other words, you got to know your worth.
You got to know it.
Know your value.
You can't give freebies.
When I tried to give people my consulting aid,
when I gave them my software,
no one took me up on it.
When I said, well, you're losing how much?
$10 million?
It's going to cost you this.
And they said, that's a lot of money.
I said, no, that's an investment.
My value is, if you pay me this, $5,000,
I'll make you $5 million.
Now it's a deal.
My value is a deal now.
So you got to help people understand your value
proposition.
This video was amazing, you guys.
But I want you to
like and subscribe for amazing content
we've got coming very, very soon.
And as I mentioned earlier, our official entrepreneur
community, the School of Mentors, hit over 1,000 members.
So if you want to be
a part of an entrepreneur community where
you can connect directly with like-minded entrepreneurs
your age.
Older, younger, to bounce ideas
off of and grow and scale
your business, the link is down in the description
of this video.
You do not want to
miss out on this at all.
Because the multimillionaires and the billionaires
that I interview every single week,
I'm hosting live calls with them on this channel.
So to join, once again,
the link's down in the description.
I can't wait to see
you guys inside of our community,
the School of Mentors.
But with that being said, we'll
see you in the next video.